Peace.
Long ago.
before the founders established
this great city of ours
that word was all but meaningless.
an ideal as elusive as a dream.
Now. 200 years later.
We are all of us living proof
that peace is indeed attainable.
The reason for this is of
course are faction system.
Erudite. Dauntless.
Amity. Candor. Abnegation.
In dividing people according
to personality and attitude
we've created a society in which
each faction plays a critical role
in maintaining the social order.
But this harmony we achieved
is now under attack from
a small but extremely dangerous
group of individuals.
We call them "Divergents".
They are in essence the worst
of what humanity used to be
rebellious. defiant. and uncontrollable.
Five days ago. a rogue
group of divergents
posing as Dauntless brutely
invaded Abnegation
in an obvious attempt
to cripple the faction
system by attacking it's
most vulnerable members.
These divergents despise our system because
they are incapable of conforming to it.
These latest rumours for example that I was
somehow behind the attack on abnegation
is nothing more that divergent propaganda.
I have devoted myself to bringing
these fugitives to justice.
I've exercised my right as acting
council leader to declare martial law
until im confident that any threat
to our security has been eliminated.
Tell Jeanine we got it.
We are all that's left of humanity.
The vast wall that encloses this city
may protect us from our toxic surroundings.
but it is up to us to confront any element
that can poison us from within.
Because when you are civilizations
last hope peace is not merely an ideal
its an obligation.
And it is up to all us to take a stand
position against it's one true enemy.
Divergents.
Amity!
We should make sure it's clear.
Tris!
Help us. help us. please!
Please help us.
you have to help us!
I'm sorry. you have to leave.
- You just don't belong here.
- It's all her fault.
You killed Will.
No...
She killed...
Mom!
You've killed us all.
- And... Three!
- Higher!
Higher. higher!
- Are you alright?
Okay everyone back to you classroom
I just wanted to do something different.
Yeah.
Well that's definitely different.
- You dont like it?
- No. I like it. I like it alot
I'm just surprised. that's all.
- What's going on. Tris?
- Nothing. I'm fine.
Just...
Still having nightmares?
No.
We're good.
You and me. I know nothing
else is. but we are.
Time for chores.
How much longer do we
have to stay here. Four?
Until we know it's
safe to leave.
- Hey.
Son!
You can't ignore me forever.
I know you're thinking about your next
move. but there are things you don't know.
Marcus. please just leave us alone.
Your mother didn't come back to
abnegation just to save you.
She died trying to hide
something from Jeanine
that something entrusted
to Abnegation
- long time ago.
- Marcus! Stop!
Whatever you want from us.
you're not gonna get it.
I'm not the enemy here.
You found it...
It was in the home of Natalie
and Andrew Prior. like you said.
Want to tell me what's inside?
A message from the founders that will
ensure the future of people who deserve it.
Divergents will destroy our society.
unless we destroy them.
And now we can.
However. only a divergent
can open this box.
Find them!
Every last one of them.
Go with happiness.
- You with happiness.
- Thank you.
Go with happiness.
I really don't know how much longer I
can do this whole peace and love thing.
It's the amity way. just try to blend in.
I'm trying to blend in.
and its just not working.
- Coming through. on you right.
Hey here we go.
Look a rainbow. It's pretty.
Pathological offendiness along without
questioning passivity. I love this place.
Thank you. Go with happiness.
- Oops. Excuse me.
- Hey tris. I really like your hair by the way.
Did you try to cut it
all short and weird...
Hey Peter. why don't you take
your food and sit down huh?
Or what?
Besides I think we all should stick together
now that we are officially fugitives.
Wait what do you mean
by official fugitives?
You don't know? You
did'nt tell Caleb?
Yesterday Jeanine announced that
the attack on Abnegation
was organized by a group of
regenade divergents And their sympathizers.
So they're blaming
this whole thing on us?
Yeah.
And Jeanine needed a
reason to petition to the
council so they could
institute martial law.
And now she had one.
Staying here at Amity is
the best option for now.
We need to keep an eye
of the ground and find
out where the rest of
the dauntless are.
- Then we can make a move.
- We need to kill Jeanine.
I know. we're not ready yet.
- Beatrice you're not being serious. right?
- No I am being serious..
I'm not gonna stop until she's dead.
Tris you can't just go
around killing people.
She's right. listen
to your sister.
Tris. I think you should go to
erudite and kill
Jeanine yourself.
I will stay with Caleb so
they don't kill him too.
What?
C'mon you know.
What you did with your parents.
Stop!!!
What do you think you're doing?
- My office! Now!
Enjoy your meal everyone. enjoy your meal.
Hey. you need to calm down.
Was I not clear that the terms of your
sanctuary here included non violence?
Well I can guarantee you nothing
like this will ever happen again.
Be that as it may. you can
no longer stay here with us.
Your presence. it is just too disruptive.
The truth is that our sanctuary was never
gonna last very long here anyways.
Was it?
With you not standing up to Jeanine.
- You don't understand us at all.
- No I do understand you.
I understand that you think you can
stay out of this but you can't.
One day she's gonna show up
and Jeanine is gonna take
whatever power you think
you have away from you.
Tris! Tris!
Look. Johanna. we need a little more time.
We need to find out where the rest of
the Dauntless are. then we can leave.
And then what? Attack Erudite?
- I will not be a part of your violence.
- No one is asking you to.
We just need a few more days.
One.
- One. what?
- One more chance.
See. to be Amity is to forgive
others. and yourself.
You're hurting Tris.
And my heart goes out to you.
I know what it's like to stand helpless
while you loose the ones you love.
But killing Jeanine will not
gonna bring your mother back.
I know you're angry. but
you're letting it consume you.
- What is it?
Stay here and keep quite.
Gentlemen. Amity welcomes you.
- To what do we owe the pleasure.
- This isn't really a social call Johanna.
- We're looking for divergents.
- I see.
Well of course. anything
we can do to help.
We need you to volunteer
your faction to be tested.
This is screening technology from Erudite.
Amity.
Not that Jeanine is heading
up yo the council the
whole improval processing
got a little easier.
- You're exceeding your jurisdiction.
- Now. Johanna.
What happened to that Amity politeness.
The easy way. or the hard way?
It's up to you.
Alright. but under protest.
Okay we're good to go!
Move it out!
All Amity report to the dome all come to
the dome for new mandatory testing.
Ok. lets go. get inside!
You know something lady?
You seem awfully stuck in that doorway.
Eric is here. We need to move now. come on.
- What's up there?
- Just my office.
There's two guards with guns.
We're going out the window?
We need to split up.
Okey. yeah.
Every man for hmself.
Good.
Hey. they're up here!
Hey. they're up here! Come
qon they're getting away!
You're ready?
- Where?
- Out the window!
I got three on foot
heading towards the dome!
- Get them low!
- Repeat. three on foot toward the dome.
Over there!
- I demand amnisty!
- Sit down! Sit down!
I believe in Abignation. it's my right!
- Detain him!
- Let's go!
Come on. keep moving!
Run!
Come on!
- Listen!
- What?
A train!
Go. go. go!
Caleb!
Keep moving.
Ammo!
Come on. go.
- Go. go!
- Caleb!
Move!
You sure know how to make an entrance!
- Factionless.
- Amity.
Oh. you stare like dogs.
I have no idea what this one is.
- Look. we just need to get to the city. thats all.
- Well to bad. the train is taken.
And you damaged our cargo.
These are Abnegation and
you are factionless right?
- Caleb!
- I used to be Abnegation.
We used the same bolts
to make cloth for you.
Are you saying that we steal from you?
No no. I'm no longer Abnegation.
so technically you're not stealing from me.
No. you're not stealing at all.
It's a questions of semantics I suppose
wether it's stealing or sharing.
- But it's all really the same.
- That's enough!
Everybody relax alright.
You've made your point.
- We'll get off your train alright.
- Guy. would everybody just relax?
Why don't we take a seat?
- I was just trying to help!
- Don't.
Yeah. this is going to be fun.
Everybody calm down alright?
Caleb.
Get off! Get off!
- You alright?
- Yup.
Are you okay?
- Tobias Eaton.
- Say it again.
Tobias Eaton.
What you know him?
I am him.
We have been looking for you.
What are they talking about? Four!
Follow me.
Tris! I'm sorry. I wanted to help.
Four! Four! Why are they looking for you?
How do they know your your name?
This is factionless.
This is insane.
Tobias!
Mother.
I thought she was dead.
Me too.
Somebody please tell me
what's going on here.
Tobias's father was very abusive.
I knew the only way I could
ever truly escape him was...
to disappear completely.
Abnegation helped me fake my death.
Anything to protect Marcus image.
But you just left him
there alone with Marcus.
I was very young.
I reached out to him about a year ago.
I felt it was finally time to reconnect.
- I'm still your mother.
- No. my mother is dead.
I went to her funeral when I was six.
And she wasn't trying to reconnect with me.
She was trying to use me.
Like you are now.
What?
She wants an army.
- An army?
- I want an alliance.
- No. what you want is revenge!
- This isn't about me.
It's about putting an
end to a system that
says one group is more
deserving than another.
This city may be surrounded by a wall
but it doesn't have to be a prison.
I think that's a bit extreme.
I mean. the factions isn't meant
to be perfect but it's hardly a prison.
Let me guess. you're Erudite?
I was Erudite.
- Are you willing to kill Jeanine?
- Absolutely.
When I was married to
Marcus I knew her well.
And believe me. there's
nothing she isn't capable of.
- But I think you already know that.
- Tris. we can't trust her.
- Maybe she knows...
- We're on the same side. Tris.
I'm factionless because I
don't fit in any one faction.
And you're Divergent because
you belong to too many..
But we are both a threat to Jeanine.
My people are ready for war
if that's what it takes.
And then what?
- We depose those in power.
- And once you've done that?
Once you killed Jeanine.
who's in power then?
You see. that's the part she
always conveniently leaves out.
Don't tell me this isn't about
you. this is only about you.
I know where the remaining
Dauntless are hiding.
- Where?
- They took shelter in Candor.
As far as I know they're still there.
Think about it. If we
were to combine forces.
Dauntless and Factionless.
we'd be unstoppable.
That's not gonna happen.
Thank you for your hospitality.
but we will be leaving in the morning.
Four. maybe this is...
Tobias. please reconsider.
Don't you call me that.
My name is Four.
You want to talk him in. or should I?
The food looks lovely.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I should've told you about her.
No more secrets.
Okay?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to wake you.
I always loved to watch him sleep.
I take it you're setting out
to Candor in the morning?
Yeah.
Listen. I only want what's best for him.
You hardly even know him.
You'd like to think
that wouldn't you?
But deep inside I think you're
scared I know him all to well.
- Im not scared.
- Of course you are.
You're scared that he'll finally
see you for what you really are.
Deadly.
You don't believe me?
Ask him.
Are you okey?
Yeah.
- Sure?
- Yeah.
- Im not going with you guys.
- What?
To Candor. I'm not going with you guys.
- What are you talking about?
- What's your plan?
You guys are gonna find the rest
of the Dauntless and then what?
You attack Erudite?
Assasinate Jeanine and start a civil war?
Im sorry. I'm just not cut out for that.
I'm not like you guys.
I need to get back to Abnegation maybe...
...Maybe I can be usefull there.
Caleb. there's nothing left in Abnegation.
Yeah.
- You okey?
- We just need to get to Candor.
Triss!
I know you think Caleb is your
responsibility but he made his own choice.
You can't protect everyone.
- I can't protect anyone.
- Nobody can.
Him leaving isn't your fault.
None of this is your fault.
Johanna was right. You
have to forgive yourself.
Thank you.
We gotta move.
- We found them!
- Yeah.
- Damn it's good to see you guys.
- How are you?
I'm better now. I'm not
exactly good for layong low.
- Triss!
- Christina!
- It's so good to see you.
- You too.
Have you heard anything about Will?
- No.
- Nothing?
No.
Something must have happened to him.
He would've found me by now you know.
- Hey.
How are you holding up?
- How many Dauntless do we have?
- 175 total.
- 175? That's it?
- The rest followed Max.
- Not nearly the number we need.
Hold it! Grab the guns!
- Hey. they're with us.
- We know who you are.
Last warning. Drop your guns.
Alright.
Easy.
- I'm Jack Kang. I'm leadership here.
- We know who you are.
We are not a threat to Candor.
That might be your truth.
it's not neccesarily mine.
All I know for certain is you are both wanted
for criminal insurgency and conspiring
in the attack on Abnegation.
Those are lies.
If you were Candor I would
take you at your word.
Unfortunately given the circumstances I'm
obliged to hand you over to the council.
- You can make your case there.
- You might as well kill us now.
If Jeanine finds us. we're not
gonna live to stand trial.
I doubt that very much.
She would never supersede the council.
Are you sure about that?
Who's gonna stop her? You?
Factional law must be upheld.
No. wait wait wait.
Can I ask you one question?
Jeanine believes that Erudite are the most
fit to govern because they are the smartest.
You believe Candor is the most fittest
to judge because you are so honest?
I admit. I hold that belief.
Then. would you say I
trial held here at Candor
would be inherently more fair
than a trial held by Erudite?
The answer is yes.
In my opinion a Candor trial would have the
greatest chance of achieving true justice.
So you are asking me to petition a
council at the great Candor...?
No. As part of Candors initation
you administer a truth serum.
Correct.
We dont technically discuss such
matters with other factions.
- It's a pretty evasive answer.
- Evasion is not dishonest.
But it's not exactly honest either.
- Yes. we possess such a serum.
- Then use it on us.
Four!
If we are guilty. we
surrender to the council.
If not. you just saved two lives.
- And gain some loyal allies.
- Alright.
But you should know the
serum can be quite brutal.
It was designed for tender applicants who
are already predisposed to honesty.
Not everyone find it so easy
to share their secrets.
- I do not want to do it.
- We have to.
Neither of us have secrets worth dying for.
Let the truth set you free.
Tobias Eaton.
You are accused of conspiring with your
fellow Dauntless in the attack on Abnegation.
Is this true?
Conspiring no.
But I did attack.
I was in simulation
controlled by Jeanine and
the rest of the Dauntless
she had recruited.
Tris found me.
She managed to break me free from the
simulation and together we fought are way out.
So you are saying that Jeanine
orchestrated this attack?
Yes.
One last thing.
If you suspected that Jeanine had corrupted
Dauntless. why didn't you just leave?
Why did you stay?
I wanted to leave.
But I fell in love with Tris Prior.
And I could not leave her.
Thank you for your Candor.
Tobias Eaton. this trial
has concluded and you are
resolved of the guilt on
the attack on Abnegation.
Miss Prior if you would.
Let the truth set you free.
Tris Prior.
Mr Eaton said you managed
to free him from the sim.
Yes.
So you were never under
the simulation yourself.
No.
How is that possible?
Because im divergent.
I see.
So you never harmed any of your fellow
Dauntless or the Abnegation?
I did.
Who?
My mom.
I watched her die first and then my dad.
They were killed trying to save me.
Miss Prior. the more you resist.
the more painfull the serum will be.
My friend... I killed my friend.
He was trying to shoot me.
And... I shot him first.
What was his name?
Will. I killed Will.
This is what happens to
people that get close to me.
They get hurt or they die.
I can't forgive myself.
Thank you for your Candor.
Tris!
Im sorry.
I told you I didnt want to do that.
- Christina.
- Go.
Go.
Abnegation sim complete.
Dauntless sim initiated.
Mam. the Divergents viable is dropping.
If we dont pull her out of
the sim soon we'll loose her.
You stop when I say so.
She's gonna do it.
She's gonna pass the sim.
Dauntless sim failed.
Divergent test subject
six is no longer viable.
Alright shut it down.
We are wasting our time.
I've been asuming all the
Divergents are the same.
But some are stronger than others.
Assign all non essential
personnel to Divergent detail.
We need to work harder.
We need to find that very special one.
Where's your scary boyfriend?
Probably out doing scary boyfriend things.
Mind if I join you?
I love heights.
Up here everyting seems
much smaller. you know.
I know it sounds crazy. but...
Sometimes I think I see
lights out beyond the wall.
I know they say its all just
wasteland out there but...
We can't be the only ones left. Can we?
C'mon!
- Got any weapons?
- No!
Coast clear. moving out!
Mommy! Mommy!
That thing hurt me?
You see? It's ok.
It's just something to help you go to
sleep. I need you to do me a favour.
You have to go to the
top of the stairs and
don't come down until
your mommy comes here.
Don't come down. Can you do that?
Be brave. ok?
Ok. go.
Hey!
Why are we the only ones awake?
Because we're Divergents.
Come on. I need your help to open this.
I need your help.
Hey!
Look who decided to show up.
It's really good to see you again.
Alright folks. nothing to be nervous about.
It's a little routine inspection.
then we all go back to our business.
Hello.
Divergent 10 %.
Shit.
You're almost normal.
That's boring.
That is not part of the mission.
So what?
As far as I'm concerned the
rest of them are still outlaws.
Let's just wrap this up quick.
The others is gonna be awake soon.
- Hi. sweetie.
- I should not...
- Divergent 40%.
- I'm afraid it's not you either.
The lady said that I should not...
The lady said that I shouldn't
have come downstairs.
Maybe you should have listened.
Enough! You still have to test her.
Jeanine stold us we have to test everyone.
- Divergent 100%.
- I'll be damned.
- What?
- She's what we've been looking for.
Bullshit.
Divergent 100%.
Get her in the veichle.
I'll alert Jeanine.
If you think you got lucky. you are wrong.
You gonna wish I killed you.
Drop your weapons!
Thank you.
It's lucky you got that gun Four.
We both know your'e not much without one.
You think you're safe now?
You're wrong.
Jeanine will never gonna
stop searching for you.
Why? What she want with her? Tell me!
It's exactly what Jeanine needs.
It's the perfect subject.
Is that supposed to scare me?
You're responsible for the
death of hundreds of people.
You know the
punishment for that.
Listen... I found a way to live
with the blood on my hands.
But can you?
Why dont they come out?
All I know is that they put me sleeping
and then all hell break lose.
Heck. don't play!
You know what this means.
Thank you.
- For helping us.
- I wish I could do more.
I had no idea Jeanine was capable
of something like this.
It's time we fight back.
- We don't have the numbers.
- We will.
Once we get the Factionless.
You heard Eric.
Jeanine is not gonna stop coming after you.
It's are only option.
Tris Prior. Of course.
It had to be her.
- Is she still off the grid?
- Yeah.
But I think I found a solution.
- It's Peter. right?
- Yeah.
Jeanine. can I just say it's truly an honor
to finally meet you in person.
Congratulations mother.
You got your war.
- I know you wish there was another way.
- But there isn't.
I'm the lesser of two evils. is that it?
- It better be.
- Tell me...
Why did you surrender to Erudite?
What do you want?
I would like a position in your regime.
Ideally I would like a position with
some advancement opportunities.
I may be Dauntless but I'm
not just some meathead.
No offense. Max.
Prove your worth to us.
Then we can discuss your ambitions.
Great.
When do I start?
Let's talk about your friend Tris Prior.
- How do I flush her out?
- It's simple.
The girl is a walking bleeding heart.
She was borne out of Abegnation.
It's her weak spot. You just
have to know how to press it.
Help! Come quick.
Traitor Tris Prior must be
surrendered to Erudite.
Or every day more death will follow.
Hand over Tris Prior.
- Or every day more death will follow.
- Christina!
No!
Christina!
Help me!
Tris!
We removed this from the
body of the suicidal.
Marlene. Her name was Marlene.
I'm sorry. Marlene.
It's a very sophisticated
sim serum injector.
It also has a radio
transmitter in it's head.
- How do we get them out?
- I don't know.
This tech was built to defend itself.
This tendril...
wraps around the nearest major artery.
If you try to removed them...
and it kills the host.
Kill the host?
So what do we do?
Tori must neutralize the disk
before we do anything else.
Or we can do the logical thing.
We hand her over.
Nobody knows about this alliance.
we have to protect that advantage.
If we hand Tris over now...
it might buy some time.
I think it's a good idea.
But you have to go through me first.
- Me too.
- And us.
I am the one with a time bomb in my arm!
I know what you're thinking.
But I'm not gonna let you do it.
I can't let anyone else die because of me.
No one else is gonna die because of you.
Tori will disable the disk.
- And if she doesn't?
- Then...
If she doesn't. we figure it out.
Together.
You know. I'm just one person.
- I'm not worth it.
- You are worth it.
You are more than worth it to me.
I love you.
This city may be safe behind a closed wall.
but make no mistake. that wall alone
doesnt ensure our security.
It's up to us. everyone of us. to remain
vigilant and isolate any threat against us.
There are individuals hiding among
us who must be contained.
Permit me to address the objections from
my fellow faction leaders.
I'm aware that there has been some concerns
about the unavoidable raid on Candor
so let me be clear.
The harbouring of
Divergents from any faction
can not be tolerated.
Very soon I will present
what I believe to be no
less than a mandates from
the founders themselves.
On this I have no doubt on the measure
I have taken to keep the peace.
I have provided instructions that will allow
us to eradicate the Divergence crisis.
Once and for all.
Where are you going?
She has left. She's gone.
What? When?
- Last night.
- Wait.
Tobias! People look to you for leadership.
You can't just abandon them
Tobias!
Wow!
I have to admit that I'm surprised.
I mean. I know that you are dumb but..
I didn't think you were dumb enough
to actually come down here.
And turn yourself in.
The killings had to stop.
That just shows that you can
take the girl from Abnigation
but you cant take Abnigation out of her.
Let's go.
Once a stiff. always a stiff. Right?
- What is this?
- What is this? This is the whole reason you are locked Tris.
Man I love knowing stuff you don't.
I need you to open that box Tris.
The only way to open that box is to
pass the sims of all five factions.
But te only people who have
tried to it so far have died.
I don't think I was
supposed to tell you that.
Well...
No pressure.
Remarkable!
The chances of it being you of all people.
You're the... laws of probability.
As remarkable as many people
you managed to murder?
Dark times call for extrme measures.
You may find it hard to believe.
But I'm serving the greater good.
Step up on the disc please.
Mam?
Stop the suicides or I
swear I will shoot him.
That's okey. You can kill him if you want.
we have plenty of guards.
What?
I'm guesing you need me alive
for this to work. Right?
Right?!
Tris.
Caleb.
Don't engage to subject.
Conditions are already less then optimal.
My God.
If I do this the suicides stop?
No. The suicides will continue.
Until you suced and pass all five sims.
That should be sufficient enough.
Good luck.
Let's begin.
Initialize the Dauntless sim.
Mom.
Tris. help me!
Heart rate is rising.
Keep her in play.
Mom!
I'm coming.
Tris!
Hold on!
Tris.
Dauntless sim complete.
- I miss you so much.
- I know you do.
But I'm still with you..
You need to be strong now.
Tell me you're gonna be strong.
- I'm trying.
- You can do this.
I know you can.
You're brave. Braver than anyone.
I'm not brave mom.
I pretend that I am.
I want people to think
that I am. but I'm not.
I'm really really scared and...
Maybe we are actually
what's wrong in this world.
Divergents.
I never wanted any of this.
You and dad and Caleb and Four.
I can't help but think that if I was normal
we would all still be together.
Mom. I don't want to be Divergent anymore.
I just want to feel safe again.
Candor sim complete.
Four. You're here?
Yeah. I'm here.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Secure the hallway.
Let's get you out of here.
- You good?
- Yeah.
Stop. Let him go.
Wait. you're not gonna shoot me?
Once a stiff. always a stiff.
Go!
Four. how did you get passed security?
You know me. scary boyfriend skills.
What is it?
You weren't there. You
didn't even hear that.
Tris.
We need to leave now. Alright?
I'm sorry Four.
- What?
- I'm sorry I didn't tell you I was gonna go.
I wanted to say goodbye.
but I just didnt know how.
- I didn't know how.
- What are you talking about?
Even though I didn't
get to say it in
real life. at least I
get to say it now.
- Even if it is just a sim.
- Tris. we're not in a sim.
Don't you think I would
know if I were in a sim?
Four... you're not in a sim.
- You're the sim.
- Wait. wait.
Erudite sim complete.
- There's only Amity now.
- She hasn't passed Abnegation yet.
Yes she has. When she spared your life.
This girl is extraordinary.
She tested positive for
four factions in one day.
No one has gotten that far.
We got a problem.
She's crashing. We have to rest her.
Are you sure you're not letting
familiar attachment cloud your judgement?
See for yourself.
Very well.
Detach the subject.
Good work. gentlemen. We
will resume tomorrow.
You were never planing on going
back to Abnegation. were you?
I had to do what I though was right.
My parents would be ashamed of you.
Well maybe not. I mean I'm
willing to sacrifice you.
The only family I have left.
The only person that I love.
In order to preserve what's
best for everyone else.
What's more selfless than that?
What does Jeanine think
is in that box Caleb?
It's a message from the founders.
But the box was to be opened
only if the factions broke down.
Which is why we require
someone like you to open it.
You're living proof
that the Divergent
problem has grown
beyond all control.
Do you even hear what you
are saying right now?
No one think it's your fault
that you were born this way.
Jeanine murdered an entire faction Caleb.
That faction could no longer be trusted.
She killed our parents.
Are parents brought that on themselves.
What are you talking about?
The box. it was in their house.
They were the ones hiding it.
All those lives could have been spared.
Seems we didnt knew our parents
as well as we thought we did.
Alright family reunion is
over. it's time to go.
I got a little surprise for you Tris.
- Four!
- Tris!
Tris!
Four!
I gather your brother explained how vital the work
you're doing here is to the future of the city.
Please just let Four go.
If his well being is such a concern you
should focus on the task at hand.
Tell me...
Do you appreciate irony?
You tested positive for Erudite so
you must have the intellectual capacity.
Irony.
For instance. Right
now you are full of
hate. but you need to
pass an Amity sim.
Then there are other ironies at work too.
- Such as the fact your cherish mother...
- Don't.
That you so dauntlessly
saved in the sim is
the reason you're in
this mess to begin with.
You're the reason I'm in this mess.
- And then there the most
pointed irony of all.
- Stop.
That Nathalie Prior not only died trying
to protect the data that I now have.
Because you stole them.
You killed her for it!
Data that she so selfishly
withheld. But her own daughter.
her beloved Divergent Tris is going to
be the one who delivered it to me.
- I said stop!
- Therefore...
your mother's death. just like
your boyfriend's death...
will mean absolutely nothing.
Don't pull her out. Not yet.
No!
Bring her back!
Bring her back.
Now!
Bring her back!
Come on!
Test subject seven is no longer viable.
I really thought you were the one.
We just...
We just have to resume are search.
Find solace in your faction. Caleb.
We are your family now.
Jeanine wanted me to show you this.
Hey. Four. can you do that thing you do?
Hey Four. that's pretty good right?
First I stole paralytic
from infirmary then I
shot her up when she was
freaking out about you.
I mean I told these guys
I was pretty smart.
I guess they should've listened.
- You're real!
- Yeah I'm real.
- What are you doing here?
- You die. I die.
Ohh... okay guys come on.
Lets go. seriously.
You can do that later.
- You're ok?
- Yeah.
- Thank you. Peter.
- Yeah whatever. No we're even. stiff.
Alright. come on let's go.
- Before Jeanine realizes we're gone.
-
- What?
- The box! We have to get the box!
Are you kidding me?
Now is not the time for souvenir tris!
Four. you have to listen to me.
It's not what Jeanine think
it is. I know it's not.
My mother would
have destroyed it.
We have to get it.
Peter. is there another way to the lab?
I mean. I have to go to the control
room to disable all the doors.
Okay you do that!
- Okay. right now?
- Yeah.
You just choose our side
whether you meant to or not.
If you want to survive. make sure we do.
Let's go!
Fuck!
No guns. It draws less attention.
- Hey.
- Hold up!
- Access Denied.
- Come on!
- Access granted.
- Let's go..
- Is that it?
- Yes.
Grab it and let's go.
- Security breach.
- What's going on?
- What's going on? What is it?
- There's been a breach in the sim room.
I want to see who the hell is in there.
- The cameras are down in that sector.
- I'll send the guards there.
Bring up every cell!
Now!
Show her.
Tori finally found a way
to get them out safely.
- How many others?
- Every last one of them.
Let's go!
Tris! Tris. come on. we gotta move.
Tris we have to move!
I can't!. I can't.
My mom died protecting
what ever is inside this.
I have to open it for her
and I think I know how.
- If we dont leave here now we're not getting out.
- I have to do this first.
I know it doesn't make much sense
but you have to trust me. please.
You have my life apparently.
Get in.
Don't move!
Initializing Amity sim.
Back again are we.
You're an even bigger
fool than your mother.
You can say whatever you want Jeanine.
But I'm not gonna fight you.
- How very Amity of you.
- I mean it.
- I'm not gonna fight you.
- Of course you're not.
You're gonna fight her.
The one you really hate.
What are you?
I'm you. Tris.
I'm the real you.
I'm not gonna fight you.
- I'll make you fight me.
- You're not me.
I am. I'm what the others see
when they're looking at you.
You killed Will and your parents.
You're deadly.
Enough!
No one's gonna love you Tris.
They're not even gonna miss you.
This world will only be
better off without you.
One less Divergent ruining things.
And no one will ever forgive
you for what you've done.
You're wrong.
Because I will.
Amity sim complete.
- No!
- No! Stop!
Initializing message.
Hello.
I come from outside the wall.
Where we have all destroyed each other.
We designed your city as an experiment.
We believed it was the only way to recover
the humanity we had lost.
And we created factions to ensure peace.
We believed that there will be those among
you who will transcend these factions.
These will be the Divergent.
They are the true purpose
of the experiment.
They are vital to humanity's survival.
If you're watching this now than at least one of
you are proof that our experiment has succeeded.
The time has come for you to emerge
from your isolation and rejoin us.
We have allowed you to believe
that you're the last of us.
but you're not.
Mankind waits for you. with hope.
beyond the wall.
- You're okay?
- Yeah.
Yes.
You're wrong about us.
We were never the problem.
We're the solution.
- Bury the box.
- What?
No one sees it. Ever.
Kill them both.
No!
Don't move.
Put your weapons down now!
- Stay!
- Do not move!
Hello. Jeanine.
Evelyn.
Impressive.
I think we're gonna like it here.
Do you honestly think the other
factions will stand for this?
Because you're so popular?
Get her out of here.
When that message gets
out it will be the end.
What message?
You'll see. I'm gonna put it
on every monitor in the city.
We have seperated you from the rest of us.
And we created factions to ensure peace.
The time has come for you to emerge
from your isolation and rejoin us.
We have allowed you to believe
that you're the last of us.
but you're not.
If you're watching this now than at least one of
you are proof that our experiment has succeeded.
Mankind waits for you. with hope.
beyond the wall.
These will be the Divergent.
They are the true purpose
of the experiment.
They are vital to humanity's survival.
You did it.
Everyone's staring at me.
You changed everything.
What now?
Only one way to find out.
Are you ready?
It's been over 200 years.
Who knows what's out there?
You'll never find out.